Guide to the Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Printed Material
  - Works - Reviews, etc
    - The Apple Cart Reviews, Aug. 19, 25, Sept. 5, 1929; 1 item + 4 leaves (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Ervine, St. John Greer: "Mr. Shaw's Superb Pantomime" August 25, 1929; Powell, Dilys: "Ideas and the Play" August 19, 1929?; and Purdom, Charles Benjamin: "Another Go At The Apple Cart" September 5, 1929 Everyman
    - GBS: Arms and the Man Film brochure, 1 item (Box 37, Folder 6)
      Four-page supplement from Illustrierte Film-Bühne publishing photographs from the German film Helden; with this is filed an illustrated article on the same film, excerpted from a periodical dated 1958
    - GBS: Arms and the Man Reviews, 1925, 1953, 1975; 1 item + 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Trewin, John Courtena y: "Shavian Joke" July 20, 1953; Hoyt, Charles Bamfield, in Official Metropolitan Guide, Nov. 1, 1925: p. 21 interview with Pedro de Cordoba, taking the part of Sergius; Bertrand, Sandra: "Remember George Bernard Shaw?" (Our Town, New York, Nov. 14, 1975; gift of Preston Beyer
    - GBS: Augustus Does His Bit Reviews, Mar. 13, [?]; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 8)
      "New York Critics on a Shaw Play"
    - Trewin, John Courtenay: Buoyant Billions Reviews, Aug. 24, Sept. 2, 1949; 5 leaves (Box 37, Folder 9)
      "Buoyant Bernard" published in John O'London's Weekly on September 2, 1949; and in Punch on August 24, 1949
    - GBS: Caesar and Cleopatra Set design, Nov. 22, 1982; 2 leaves (Box 37, Folder 10)
      One blueprint, one photocopy of designs for production at the Shaw Festival, Niagara-on-the-Lake
    - GBS: Candida Reviews, advertisements, Feb. 7, 1925, 1937; 5 leaves (Box 37, Folder 11)
      Fabre, Eugène. Candida de Shaw. n.d.; J., J. Candida. n.d.; Morgan, Charles. Of Miss Ann Harding as Candida. 1937; The Literary Digest, Feb. 7, 1925. "The Acting in 'Candida'"
    - GBS: Cashel Byron's Profession Reviews, Criticism, advertisements, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Advertisement from Walter Scott
    - GBS: The Chocolate Soldier. Book of words for the opera, 1910; 1 item, 52 pages (Box 37, Folder 13)
      London; written by Rudolf Bernauer and Leopold Jacobson; English version by Stanislaus Stange; The Chocolate Soldier is based on Shaw's Arms and the Man
    - GBS: Collected Letters: 1874-1897 Reviews, 1965, 1966; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 14)
      Stanley Weintraub in the Saturday Review, November 13, 1965, pp. 45 and 67; with unsigned review in Time, January 21, 1966, pp. 83-84
    - GBS: Collected Letters: 1911-1925 Reviews, 1985; 3 leaves + 3 (Box 37, Folder 15)
      John Carey in The Sunday Times(London), June 2, 1985 (with caricature of Shaw based on photo in the Burgunder Collection); John Gross in The New York Times, June 18, 1985; Hugh Kenner in The New York Times Book Review, June 30, 1985; Samuel Hynes in The New Republic, July 15 & 22, 1985
    - GBS: Collected Plays with Their Prefaces Reviews, Nov. 2, 1975; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 16)
      John Simon in The New York Times Book Review, November 2, 1975; with Warren S. Smith's "G.B. Shaw at 119 - Indication of Immortality" (NY Times, November 2, 1975)
    - GBS: Cymbeline Refinished Reviews, advertisements, May 28, 1938?; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 17)
      "Shaw Tells Why He Revised Bard."
    - GBS: The Devil's Disciple Reviews, 1897; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 18)
      Albert White Vorse in Gallery of Plays and Players, No. 12. New York, 1897
    - GBS: Diaries Reviews, criticism, advertisements, Feb. 5, 1964; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 19)
      Cullen, Tom. A. "Diaries of Shaw Boring Documents." February 5, 1964 Times-Leader
    - GBS: The Doctor's Dilemma Reviews, Criticism, advertisements, n.d.; 2 items (Box 37, Folder 20)
      Advertisements from Constable & Co.
    - GBS: Everybody's Political What's What? Reviews, Sept. 17, 1944; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 21)
      Brown, Ivor. "All About All."
    - GBS: Far-Fetched Fables Reviews, criticisms, 1948, 1950; 4 leaves (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - GBS: The Fascinating Foundling Reviews, criticisms, 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - GBS: Florence Farr, Bernard Shaw and W.B. Yeats Reviews, Criticisms, Mar. 7, 1942; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 24)
      The Times Literary Supplement
    - GBS: Geneva Reviews, advertisements, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 25)
      Flyer from Constable advertising the first edition
    - GBS: Getting Married Reviews, May 13, 1908; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 26)
      "Shaw's Getting Married." n.d.; The Daily Telegraph, May 13, 1908 (2 copies)
    - GBS: Back to Methuselah Reviews, Criticism, 1924, 1946, 1947; 6 leaves (Box 37, Folder 27)
      Unsigned review, in the London Times? of a performance at the Court Theatre; apparently to be dated Feb. 20, 1924
    - GBS: Heartbreak House Reviews, 1921, 1943, 1951; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 28)
      Ervine, St. John. "Mr. Shaw in Despair." October 23, 1921 The Observer; Farjeon, Herbert. "Bernard Shaw's Best Play." April 9, 1943. John O'London; Pearson, Hesketh. "...Shaw's favourite play." April 6, 1951. Radio Times
    - GBS: How He Lied To Her Husband Reviews, Criticisms, Sept. 27, 1904; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 29)
      The Sun New York
    - GBS: In Good King Charles's Golden Days Reviews, May 10, 1940; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 30)
      "Bernard Shaw and a Biographer."
    - GBS: The Inca of Perusalem Reviews, Apr. 17, 1959; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 31)
      Ein leichtes Spiel mit schweren Dingen (April 17, 1959; Die Tat, Zürich)
    - GBS: The Intelligent Woman's Guide to Socialism Reviews, Criticism, advertisements, Aug. 18, 1930, [?] 10, 1931; 4 leaves (Box 37, Folder 32)
      Ad from Book-of-the-Month Club
    - GBS: The Irrational Knot Reviews, Oct. 26, 1905; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 33)
      Books and Bookishness, by C.W. Mason (article inscribed to Shaw by Mason, from The Brooklyn Daily Eagle October 26, 1905)
    - GBS: Jitta's Atonement Reviews, Jan. 27, 1925; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 34)
      "G.B.S." Opens up New Field; January 27, 1925 Daily News
    - GBS: John Bull's Other Island Reviews, July 6, 1951; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 35)
      Ervine, St. John. "John Bull's Other Island." July 6, 1951
    - GBS: Major Barbara Film souvenir program, n.d.; 2 items (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - GBS: Major Barbara Reviews, Mar. 6, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 37)
      "'Major Barbara' Revived."
    - GBS: Man and Superman Reviews, Criticism, 1903, 1952, 1977; 4 leaves (Box 37, Folder 38)
      Pearson, Hesketh. "The Comedy Shaw Wrote Around his Gospel." n.d.; Eder, Richard. "Shaw Still Has the Power to Captivate." ( New York Times, September 4, 1977); Punch, September 16, 1903; Coda, July 1952 (advert for a Columbia recording of Don Juan in Hell, read by Charles Laughton, Charles Boyer, Cedric Hardwicke, and Agnes Moorehead)
    - GBS: Man and Superman Costume design - Ann Whitefield, 1977; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 39)
      8.5 x 11.5 color print for Ann Whitefield's costume in Act IV; with identification added on verso
    - GBS: Misalliance Reviews, Feb. 24, 1910; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 40)
      Daily Telegraph, February 24, 1910; deacidified August 1984
    - GBS: Document: Box office receipts from the 1908 American tour of Mrs. Warren's Profession, 5 leaves (Box 37, Folder 41)
      Pittsburgh, and Appleton
    - GBS: Mrs. Warren's Profession Film brochure, 1959; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 42)
      8-page supplement from Illustrierte Film-Bühne providing many photographs from the German film Frau Warrens Gewerbe
    - GBS: Mrs. Warren's Profession Reviews, July 8, 1908, Oct. 7, 1925; 1 leaf + 2 (Box 37, Folder 43)
      Wilhelm Michel in Münchner Neueste Nachrichten, No. 314, July 8, 1908, p. 2; E?V? Knox, in Punch October 7, 1925
    - GBS: O'Flaherty V.C. Reviews, Dec. 12, 1920; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 37, Folder 44)
      Ervine, St. John. "The Secret History of O'Flaherty V.C. December 12, 1920 in The Observer
    - GBS: The Philanderer Reviews, Dec. 29, 1913; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 45)
      New York Tribune, December 29, 1913; New York Sun, December 29, 1913; New York Herald, December 29, 1913; all deacidified August 1984
    - GBS: Preface to Great Expectations Reviews, Aug. 14, 1947; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 46)
      Russell, John. "Mr. Shaw on Dickens." August 14, 1947
    - GBS: Prefaces Reviews, Aug. 17, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 47)
      Ervine, St. John. "Mr. Shaw Sums Himself Up." August 17, 1934 in The Observer
    - GBS: Pygmalion, May 5, 10, 1958; 3 leaves (Box 37, Folder 48)
      Mander, R., Mitchenson, J. "Shaw's Borrowed Plot." May 10, 1958 in Daily Telegraph; Darlington, W. A. "Fairer than Shaw to his Lady." May 5, 1958 in Daily Telegraph
    - GBS: The Quintessence of Ibsenism Reviews, Criticisms, advertisements, Oct. 1907; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 49)
      Ad from S. Fischer, Verlag, Berlin
    - GBS: Rhyming Picture Guide to Ayot St. Lawrence Reviews, criticisms, 1950?; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - GBS: Saint Joan Reviews, criticisms, Feb. 21, 1945; 2 leaves (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - GBS: The Shewing-Up of Blanco Posnet Reviews, Criticisms, Feb. 18, 1911; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 51)
      Noguchi, Yone. Western Drama in the East. The Graphic, February 18, 1911
    - GBS: The Shewing-Up of Blanco Posnet Reviews, criticisms, 1909; 5 items (Box 37, Folder 52)
      Five newspaper cuttings dated May 22, August 21, 22, 24, 26; the cutting of May 9 reports an interview with Shaw; that of Aug. 24 prints a letter from Shaw to W.B. Yeats dated Aug. 22, as well as letters to and from Lady Gregory
    - GBS: The Simpleton of the Unexpected Isles Reviews and advertisements, Mar. 8, 11, 1945; 4 leaves (Box 37, Folder 53)
      Flyer from Constable advertising the first edition of The Simpleton, The Six, and The Millionairess
    - GBS: Sixteen Self-Sketches Reviews, Mar. 4, 12, 1949; 7 leaves (Box 37, Folder 54)
    - GBS: Too True To Be Good, 1932; 1963; 10 items (Box 37, Folder 55)
      "F., R.J." "G.B.S. Defents Too True from Failure." October 28, 1932 in Daily Telegraph; London Times August 7, 1932; E.A. Baughan, News Chronicle, August 8, 1932; James Agate, Sunday Times, September 18, 1932; London Times, August 11, 1932; Hobe, Variety, March 20, 1963; Melvin Maddocks, Christian Science Monitor, March 15, 1963
    - GBS: Translations and Tomfooleries Reviews, November 1926?; 3 items (Box 37, Folder 56)
      "Mr. Shaw at Play." November [1926?] in Times LIterature Supplement
    - GBS: Widowers' Houses Reviews, Criticisms, advertisements, 1938?; 4 leaves (Box 37, Folder 57)
      Williams, Stephen, "'Widowers' Houses': Play or Pamphlet?" n.d.; Ad from Independent Theatre Series
    - GBS: You Never Can Tell Reviews, criticisms, Oct. 4, 1947; 1 leaf (Box 37, Folder 58)
    - GBS: Works of George Bernard Shaw, n.d.; 20 items (Box 37, Folder 59)
      Advertisements, publisher's catalogues, solicitations, etc.; not related to any particular work by Shaw; filed at bottom of box marked: "Misc. Printed Material" Works of George Bernard Shaw
- Series VII. Reviews on G.B. Shaw
  - Reviews on G.B. Shaw (Box 38)
  - Reviews on G.B. Shaw (Box 39)
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous Printed Material by others
  - A - C
    - Adcock, Arthur St. John: Bernard Shaw's New Plays, May 1911; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Article, printed on pp. 94-95 of The Bookman on The Doctor's Dilemma, Getting Married, and The Shewing-Up of Blanco Posnet; on pp. 95-96 os the same issue is printed "A Long Way with Bernard Shaw" by Holbrook Jackson, a review of George Bernard Shaw: A Critical Biography by Archibald Henderson
    - Abby Theatre Dramatic Festival of Plays and Lectures: Brochure, Aug., 1938; 1 item (44 p.) (Box 40, Folder 1.4)
      Dublin; Official Souvenir of the third (enlarged) edition of the brochure giving the program for the Dramatic Festival in August, 1938.
    - Abby Theatre Fund: Flyer, 1921; 1 item + 1 (Box 40, Folder 1.5)
      Announcement of the Abbey Theatre's fund-raising lectures in London, 1921. With not by Dan H. Laurence. Mrs. Warren's Profession
    - American Shaw Festival: Brochure, 1982; 5 leaves + envelope (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Announcement of the Inaugural Season; plays by Shaw included are Candida and Mrs. Warren's Profession
    - American Shaw Festival: Brochure, 1983; 3 leaves + envelopes (Box 40, Folder 3)
      Plays by Shaw included are Misalliance and How He Lied To Her Husband
    - American Shaw Festival: Brochure, 1984; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 4)
      The play by Shaw included is Major Barbara
    - The Anglo-Swedish Literary Foundation: First Annual Report, ca. Apr. 1, 1928; 1 leaf + 2 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Gift of Dan H. Laurence; with the Second Annual Report (ca. April 1, 1929) and a mimeographed summary, dated June 1960, of the Foundation's activities
    - Anonymous: Mr. George Bernard Shaw [biographical notice accompanying Shaw's portrait], 1898; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 6)
      In English portraits: a series of...; London, Grant Richards
    - Archer, William: About the Theatre. "The Doctor's Dilemma.", Dec. 19, 1906; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 7)
      Excerpted from The Tribune; deacidified on August 1984
    - Archer, William: The Future of the Drama, June 3, 1912; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Excerpted from Yomiuri Shimbun; report in Japanese of lecture by Archer; with explanatory note added on separate leaf by Dan H. Laurence
    - Archer, William: Letter: to the Editor, the Pall Mall Gazette, Oct. 19, 1891; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Concerns Archer's "dramatic works." Archer was a close friend of Shaw
    - The Arts Theatre Club: Letter to Members, Dec. 1946; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 10)
      Includes an announcement that G.B. Shaw's Back to Methuselah will be presented in its entirety
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: "Shaw's Hidden Qualities.", Nov. 5, 1950; 2 items (Box 40, Folder 11)
      Excerpted from The Observer; 2 copies of article
    - The Authors' Producing Society: Circular concerning Damaged Goods[proof], ca. March 1914; 3 leaves + 1 (Box 40, Folder 12)
      Announces transfer of production of the play Damaged Goods, by Eugène Brieux, to the Court Theatre; Shaw's Preface to Three Plays by Brieux is quoted on galley 3; with explanatory note added by Dan H. Laurence on separate leaf
    - Beerbohm, Max: Caricature of Shaw, reproduced from Beerbohm's copy of Shaw's The Doctor's Dilemma, 1920; 2 items (Box 40, Folder 13)
      In Columbia library columns. New York. February 1974. Vol. XXIII, No. 2, p. 2; included is an article on the Jack Harris Samuels Library, which contains Shaw material; 2 copies includes reprint
    - Bell, Robert Anning: Bookplates of Jane Patterson, n.d.; 2 items (Box 40, Folder 14)
      Two bookplates designed by Bell for Jane Patterson
    - Bering-Jensen, Helle: "The Fashioning of charlatan Shaw", Oct. 10, 1988; copy; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Bermann, Richard A.: Der Ire Bernard Shaw, Apr. 6, 1914; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 16)
      In Der Zeitgeist, Beiblatt zum "Berliner Tageblatt" April 6, 1914
    - Bindon, Graham: The Builder of Idols; part 1 of George Bernard Shaw: Two Views, 1951; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 17)
      In the Clare Market Review (London). 21cm. Vol. XLVI, No. 2, p. 30-32
    - Bishop, George Walter: Portrait of Shaw as a Villager, Jan. 1, 1962; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 18)
      Excerpted from Daily Telegraph; review of Allan Chappelow's book Shaw the Villager and Human Being
    - Blatchford, Robert: The New Enemy in Our Midst, Nov. 22, 1914; 1 item + 12 leaves (Box 40, Folder 19)
      Full-page article printed in The Weekly Dispatch on p. 3, largely an attack on G. Bernard Shaw's pamphlet Common Sense about the War; the original is FRAGILE: with it are filed two complete photocopies, on eon acid-free paper
    - Borough Polytechnic Institute Economic Club: Program of lectures, 1896; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 20)
      "A lecture by G. Bernard Shaw on "The Jevonian Theory" is scheduled for Dec. 2."
    - Braddock, Joseph: "Shaw's Austrian Ambassador", July 10, 1953; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 21)
      Review of Chronicle of a Life, by Siegfried Trebitsch, Shaw's German translator
    - Brock, Erich: Bernard Shaw vor dem Klostergitter, Nov. 19, 1958; 2 leaves (Box 40, Folder 22)
      Berlin?; article in two parts from unidentified periodical, reviewing the book In a Great Tradition(London 1956) concerning Laurentia McLachlan and Shaw, as translated into German under the title: Freiheit jenseits des Gitters
    - Brock, H.T.: "Shaw the Youthful Pictured by Shaw", Sept. 7, 1930; 3 leaves (Box 40, Folder 23)
      In New York Times Magazine; article on Shaw's life and work, commemorating the publication of the Collected Works, by William H. Wise & Co.; included are prints of 5 photos of Shaw
    - Brock, H.T.: "Weighed in the Ballance", Nov.21, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 40, Folder 23.5)
      In New York Times Book Review Magazine; review on Frank Harris' unauthorized biography of Shaw
    - Brome, Vincent: "Bernard Shaw versus H.G. Wells", n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 24)
      In Radio Times; printed with the article are portraits of the two by David Low
    - Brown, Ivor John Carnegie: "The Future of G.B.S.", Nov. 5, 1950; 2 items (Box 40, Folder 25)
      In The Observer
    - Callen, Harold: The Bashful Genius, Theatre Program, May 22-June 10, 1979; 1 item + 2 leaves (Box 40, Folder 26)
      Program and poster for a play (The Van Dam Theatre, New York) about Shaw; with note added on separate leaf from Bernard F. Burgunder; gift of Dan H. Laurence
    - Carter, Huntly: Price of Hero Worship, Mar. 11, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 27)
      In The Daily Express; newspaper article about market value of cards and letters by Shaw, with references to letters from Shaw to Carter; deacidified August 1984
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Drawing by Ginsbury of Mrs. Campbell as "the Matriarch" in G.B. Stern's play of the same name, June 1, 1929; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 28)
      In T.P.'s Weekly
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: "Speech Has Become Talk - and Talk Chatter", July 8, 1927; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 29)
      In The Evening Standard; holograph notation at the top, "Is it very bad?" in Mrs. Campbell's hand
    - Campion, Sidney Ronald: Letter to News Chronicle, Nov. 21, 1950; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 30)
      In News Chronicle; titled: "G.B.S. wrote..." beside the printed letter is reproduced in facsimile Shaw's Autograph Letter Signed to Campion, October 23, 1947, concerning disposal of his ashes
    - Chappelow, Allan: "Photographing the Fabians", May 7, 1954; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 31)
      In John O'London's Weekly; includes photos of H.G. Wells, E.R. Pease, the Webbs, and Shaw; it was done to commemorate the 70th anniversary of the founding of the Fabian Society
    - Charles Hamilton Galleries, Inc.: Auction catalogs 163 & 164, Apr. 19 & May 31, 1984; 2 items (Box 40, Folder 32)
      Lots 101-132 in the catalog for April 19 are letters from George Bernard Shaw to Arnold Daly; the catalog for May 31 lists the prices realized at the April 19 sale
    - Churchill, Sir Winston Leonard Spencer: The Amazing George Bernard Shaw, Aug. 1946; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 33)
      In Adam International Review; Churchill's article (pp. 1-4) is followed with contributions on Shaw by Sybil Thorndyke, C.E.M. Joad, James Agate, Denis Saurat, F.E. Loewenstein; F.E.L.'s article quotes from drafts of Shaw's letters of 1879-80
    - Clement, Russell: The Perfect Wagnerite, Summer 1978; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 34)
      Friends of the Brigham Young Unversity Library Newsletter; article on a copy of Shaw's Perfect Wagnerite, inscribed to Dorothea Kreyer and containing 30 photographs of her and Shaw from the summer of 1898; gift of Rick Grunder
    - Cockerell, Sir Sydney Carlyle: Document: Admission card to cremation of George Bernard Shaw, Nov. 4, 1950; 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 35)
      Card issued by The Public Trustee Office for the cremation on November 6, 1950
    - Collis, John Stuart: "Bernard Shaw at Eighty", Aug. 1, 1936; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 36)
      In John O'London's Weekly
    - Communiqué: Bernard F. Burgunder '18 Loves Bernard Shaw, Sept. 1980; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 37)
      Article printed on page 2 of Communiqué concerning Bernard Burgunder and the Burgunder Shaw Collection
    - Communiqué: Burgunder Shaw Collection Receives Valuable Addition, Spring 1985; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 38)
      Article printed, with pictures, on page 11, about the Black Girl Collection
    - Communiqué: Valuable Shaw letter added to Burgunder Collection, Mar. 1979; 1 item (Box 40, Folder 39)
      Article printed on page 9 of Communiqué, concerning Shaw's letter to Kate Perugini, June 2, 1903
    - Contemporary Arts Conference: Preliminary Notice, June 1921; 1 item + 1 leaf (Box 40, Folder 40)
      A 7-page stapled printed pamphlet including the program for the conference to be held June 7-10, 1921; with G.B. Shaw's holograph notes on back cover; identifying note in ink on front cover by Holbrook Jackson; and a note on separate leaf by Dan H. Laurence
    - The Cornhill Magazine: Index to Volume 168. Numbers 1003-1008; Spring 1955-Summer 1956; John Murray, 50 Albermarles Street, London, W.I. 1956, 1 item (Box 40, Folder 41)
      Cover and the table of contents; this is the magazine which contains the letters between Shaw and Dame Laurentia MacLachlan
  - D - I
    - Dent, Alan: Wicked Wicked Letters, [1952]; 7 leaves (Box 41, Folder .5)
      In Life Magazine; edited by Dent, a review of the "Shaw-Terry Letters", pp. 62-[69?] with examples of their letters and photographs of both.
    - Dickens, Charles: Dickens and Ellen Ternan, Mar. 8, 15, & 22, 1953; 3 items (Box 41, Folder 1)
      In The Sunday Times; articles concerned with Dicken's relationship to Ellen Ternan; obtained by Mr. Burgunder for their connection with the Shaw-Perugini correspondence
    - Downer, Alan S.: Harley-Granville-Barker, Autumn 1947; copy; 20 leaves (Box 41, Folder 2)
      In The Sewanee Review; Sewanee, Tennessee, Autumn, 1947. 22.5 cm. Vol. LV, no. 4, p. 627-645
    - Dublin. National Gallery of Ireland: Postcards, various dates; 8 items (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Postcard reproductions of eight paintings bought with the George Bernard Shaw Fund, a part of Shaw's bequest
    - Du Cann, C.G.L.: Shaw's Unpublished Diaries, Nov. 1958; 1 item (Box 41, Folder 4)
      In The Humanist; article printed on pp. 9-12
    - Untitled, 1 item + 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Emery, Mrs. Florence (Farr): "The Latest Ibsen Actress", July 23, 1891; 1 item (Box 41, Folder 6)
      In The Pall Mall Gazette; from Miss Farr's clipping service?
    - Ervine, St. John Greer: A Forgotten "Masterpiece", Mar. 3, 1929; 1 item (Box 41, Folder 7)
      In The Stage World; column headed "At the Play" concerning the anonymous play Alan's Wife(produced in 1893); includes the text (corrected in hand of Dan H. Laurence) of Letter to Floryan Sobieniowski, November 10, 1928
    - Ervine, St. John Greer: "At the Play: The Alleged Septuagenarianism of Bernard Shaw", 1926; 1 item (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Ervine, St. John Greer: "At the Play. Frank Harris on Bernard Shaw", Nov. 29, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 9)
      In Observer; a review of Frank Harris' book Bernard Shaw
    - Ervine, St. John Greer: G.B.S. in the Theatre, July 12, 1956; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 10)
      In The Listener
    - Ervine, St. John Greer: Mr. Shaw on Extermination - I, Feb. 18, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 11)
      In London Observer; printed under the heading "At the Play" and being in part a review of Shaw's Village Wooing
    - Escott, T.H.S.: "How the 'World' Was Made", Aug. 7, 1895; 1 item (Box 41, Folder 12)